<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- the line above is the "XML declaration"; it is not -->
<!-- required, but we recommend using it -->
<?xml-model href="../schemas/exercise.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="../schemas/exercise.isosch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- the two lines above are processing instructions for finding the schema; -->
<!-- they are intended for oXygen, but other software might use them, also -->
<?xml-stylesheet title="TEI Boilerplate" type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<!-- the line above is a processing instruction that asks that -->
<!-- this file be transformed by "teibp.xsl" -->
<?xml-stylesheet title="your own CSS"    type="text/css" href="../css/tiny_TEI_template.css" alternate="yes"?>
<!-- the line above is a processing instruction that asks that -->
<!-- this file be styled by "tiny_TEI_template.css" -->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" >
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title><!-- put title here --></title>
        <author>
          <persName><!-- author's name here --></persName>
        </author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher><!-- publisher here --></publisher>
        <availability>
          <ab><!-- copyright or copyleft information here --></ab>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <!-- source information here; better yet, use a <biblStruct> instead -->
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <front>
      <!-- front matter, if any, goes in <div>s, here -->
    </front>
    <body>
     <div><open><p><title>AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS.<title><p>

<p><subtitle>NO. 3.<subtitle><p>

<p><persName><subject><author>R. H. Dana.<author><subject><persName><p>

<p>If fancy (as we justly conceive the case to be) represent
the leading traits in the intellectual constitution of <persName><author>Mr.
Willis<author><persName>: <emphasis>sentiment<emphasis>, we apprehend, with no less characteris-
tic force, forms the most prominent features in the genius
and writings of <persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana<author><subject><persName>. No mere sentimentalist, our au-
thor is emphatically a man of sentiment: no hypocritical <persName><author>Jo-
seph Surface<author><persName>, full of cant and moral pretensions, but a genu-
ine man of feeling, unlike, or rather superior to, <persName><author>Mackenzie’s<author><persName>
hero, in being, in addition, a true philosophic observer of
life and character, a stem self-student, and, a powerful
painter, according to the stereotyped phrase, of men and
manners.<p>

<p>This attribute of sentiment, in the instance of our author,
is at one and the same time, a moral and an intellectual
quality, religious, high-toned, upright, masculine, partaking
of the softness of <persName><author>Mackenzie<author><persName> and the stern dignity of <persName><author>Words-
worth<author><persName>. Apart from this faculty, <persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana<author><subject><persName> is a writer of
great purity and power, of much acuteness and elegance in
other walks than in those of philosophic sentiment or of
sentimental description; but in those he is a master, and
ranks first among his contemporaries and countrymen. He
has vast powers in depicting the struggles of the darker pas-
sions, jealousy, hatred, suspicion and remorse. <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName>
has touches of Byronnic force, and discloses a similar vein to
that so fully opened and with such popular effect in the
works of <persName><author>Godwin<author><persName> and <persName><author>Chas. Brockden Brown<author><persName>.<p>

<p>This, however, is what one would call, perhaps, with a
certain degree of innocence, the uncomfortable portion of
<persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana’s<author><subject><persName> genius, and of which the tendency is doubtful.
It is an open literary question, as to the extent that such
characters as that of <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName> should be taken, for the de-
lineation of real characters. An idiot, a madman, a mono-
maniac, may be made very effective in vigorous description,
but is not the simple-hearted <persName><character>Jonathan Fords<character><persName>, for example,
a better character both for study and imitation? Doubtless
more than one <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName> has birds, but we do not go to
nature, in bad extravagances or capricious words, for instruc-
tion or delight—else the records of a Prison or a Lunatic
Asylum would form the truest volumes of history, instead of
merely furnishing a few supplementary chapters of strange
idiosyncrasies, or morbid developments. But, we have no
idea of going into a deep question of psychological criticism
at present; merely remarking that we have not the remotest
idea of any, but the purest intention, in the mind of the crea-
tor of that wretched man, as he has himself called him, and
yet from false sympathy or an unhappy bias, that way, the
readers of that most terrible history may become unaware so
strangely interested in the character and fate of the hero, as
to feel the ill effects of such an unmanly weakness long after
he had hurriedly perused the story—the wonderful truth and
fidelity of the analysis of the heart, and the vivid description
of the darkest passions, set off and release the hateful moral
deformity of the diabolical passions, that festers and finally ut-
terly corrupts the heart of their victim. Otherwise, as a
picture of naked hideousness, the tale could be read only by
the wisest and the weakest.<p>

<p>The sentiments of the writer even in the midst of these
harrowing scenes, comes in as an angel during a whirlwind
excited by the most malicious fiends in hell, spreading a hea-
venly calm, and casting a pure bright effulgence over an at-
mosphere of gloom and despair.<p>

<p>In <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName>, <persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana<author><subject><persName> has exhibited power in depicting
passion, as well as sentiment: and the same criticism ap-
plies to his <persName><character>Thornton<character><persName>, though in a much inferior degree.
Yet he is most at home in pictures of domestic life; in de-
scribing the charm of home scenes, in realizing the ideal of
conjugal felicity. Strange, that the author, who as a man is
so enthusiastic on such a theme, should, as a poet, (for he is
one as much in <persName><character>Tom Thornton<character><persName> and <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName>, as in <title>the
Buccaneers<title>,) delight in pictures, also, of gloom, of crime, of
remorse.<p>

<p>Sentiment furnishes the key, also, to the criticisms of
<persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>. We noticed this in his lectures a few winters since
on the poets and dramatists. He finds this, his favorite facul-
ty, beautifully expressed by the ballad writers and the Shaks-
perian dramatists among the old writers; and by <persName><author>Words-
worth<author><persName> and <persName><author>Coleridge<author><persName>, among the new; and to them he has
given his heart. The single critical paper in the volume of
<persName><subject><author>Dana’s<author><subject><persName> selected works, on the acting of <persName><artist>Kean<artist><persName>, is full of it, no less
than of acuteness and deep insight into the mysteries of art,
both of which indeed are colored and refined by it, to a point
and degree that may be honestly declared as not being very
far distant from perfection. The paper is almost equal in its
way, to <persName><artist>Elia’s<artist><persName> admirable miniature sketches: differing, as
widely in spirit, as they resemble each other in execution.<p>

<p>As a writer of sentiment, love, in its forms both of senti-
ment and passion, (for it varies in different natures, and is the
offspring of the temperaments of the affections and of the
fancy, according to the individual constitution, mental or mor-
al, or sensitive of the recipient and cherisher of it,) constitutes
the staple of <persName><subject><author>Dana’s<author><subject><persName> inventions and speculations—of love in
all of its degrees, he is a delicate limner or a vigorous pain-
ter, according as the subject is a delicate woman or a manly
man: a quiet, retired, meditative nature, or a stirring, active,
ambitious character. The female character has full justice
done it, by the writer of <title>Edward and Mary<title>. Judging from
his writings on this subject, Mr. Dana has been a happy man.
Yet he can paint a weak credulous mother, or a dashing,
heartless woman of fashion (see <persName><character>Tom Thornton<character><persName>) with as
subtle skill as he can delineate the fond, confiding heart, the
clear and wise judgment, the gentle and amiable tastes, of
a true woman and a good wife.<p>

<p>We have other points to speak of, than that only of our au-
thor’s sentiments, however, and must not dwell too long on
that.<p>

<p><persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana<author><subject><persName> has been connected in ties of literature and fami-
ly connection, with the first artist and finest poet of our
country. <persName><artist><author>Allston<author><artist><persName> and <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> married sisters, and remained to
the last intimate associates. We have heard <persName><subject><author>Mr. D.<author><subject><persName> speak of
his works out at <placeName>Cambridgeport<placeName> (we think where <persName><artist><author>Allston<author><artist><persName> re-
sided) and his conversations there with the Poet Painter, as
among his richest pleasures, nor should we forget that <persName><author>Bry-
ant<author><persName> was the early associate, as he remains the "oldest friend
of our author. Some of <persName><subject><author>Dana’s<author><subject><persName> finest portrait contributions,
were included in <persName><author>Bryant’s<author><persName> <title>New York Review<title>. The father,
too, is happy in a son who has written one of the best books<pb>
of its class since the world renowned fiction of <persName><author>De Foe<author><persName>. With
these connections to boast of, the nobility of genius has had
to contend with comparative neglect and poverty: sure ever
of a high place in the esteem and admiration of good critics,
honest readers and worthy men, whose applause constitutes
his fame, but who have little else to give beyond sympathy
and respect.<p>

<p>The late reviews of American novelists, in the <title>Quarterly<title>,
just and fair in the main, was yet guilty of omissions that
should have been noticed at the time, and filled up by a
competent critic. It is not our purpose, at present, to occupy
the whole ground, nor fill the entire vacancy—that is to be
left to the writer, who can honestly appraise the merits of
the authors less unnoticed, in a sort of article supplementa-
ry. Three comic writers, at least as worthy of notice as <persName><author><woman>Miss
Leslie<woman><author><persName>,—<persName><author><woman>Neale<woman><author><persName>, <persName><author><woman>Matthews<woman><author><persName>, and the author of <title>Harry Fran-
co<title>, our best comic satirists since <persName><author>Paulding’s<author><persName> <title>Salmagundi<title>,
have escaped notice entirely; while two serious writers, of
unquestionable excellence, <persName><author>Allston<author><persName> in his <title>Monaldi<title>, and <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>,
in certain prose dramas, among prose fictions, what the
masterpieces of <persName><author>Heywood<author><persName> or <persName><author>Middleton<author><persName> would prove by the
side of the Shaksperian drama, have been passed by without
ever attracting a casual remark.<p>

<p>This neglect may furnish some excuse for the foregoing
remarks and the critical observations that may follow, al-
beit, we had hoped the task might have been committed to
other hands. Nor shall we attempt to disentangle the mesh-
es of the tales themselves; skilful unwinding of the thread
of a narrative, or the decomposition of a plot, or an analysis
of the conduct of the incidents, ranking in our opinion, when
well done, almost with the original poem that gave birth to
the fiction. And as we do not write tales, but merely criti-
cisms upon them, we shall speak of the qualities displayed
in the construction of these narratives, rather than the inci-
dents or the characters they contain. Another and an equal-
ly good reason, as it appears to us, for the present sketch,
may be found in the fact, that our authors had been gradu-
ally lost sight of by the generation of readers that have risen
since he wrote. To a large number, we fear, nothing of
<persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> is known beyond his name; with whom, too, his name
is getting to be matter of tradition. It is now nearly a quar-
ter of a century, since we have seen anything in print by the
author of <title>the Idle Man<title>. During which period so many can-
didates for public honor and claimants for a niche in the
temple of fame have been pouring in, that the public eye is
well nigh clouded by the sparkling ephemerida, and the
public ear confounded by loud clamors and noisy appeals.
In the midst of this hubbub, the silent speculative genius
of <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>, and the power, the purity, and the classic genius
of <persName><subject><author>Dana’s<author><subject><persName> writings, have passed almost unregarded.—
Among the thousands who devour <persName><author>James<author><persName>, the tens who
study <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> may be easily enumerated; the lovers of his-
torical melo-drama, see nothing in simple, undisguised,
unaffected, yet most real and vigorous, true dramatic paint-
ing. Perhaps the American is too much of a philosopher for
those readers, who are captivated by detailed narrative and
circumstantial description; though, as a mere writer of tales
full of striking characters, closely crowded with stirring in-
cidents, set in a frame of poetic description, and enshrined
within a halo of imagination, <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> is in the first rank of no-
velists. It is wrong to speak of him as a mere tale writer:
for his tales are not only as long as certain short novels (as
long and longer than <title>Rasselas<title>, <title>Zadig<title>, <title>Candide<title>, <title>the Man of
Feeling<title>, or the admirable fictions of <persName><author>Richter<author><persName>, <persName><author>Zschokke<author><persName>,
and other German novelists) but they are as closely woven,
that they read sometimes like abstracts of longer works.
There is nothing to be spared; the utmost economy is ob-
served, consistent with real richness and vigor. Yet, as we
said, the evident philosophic character of the author, the
basis, indeed, of his portrait character, as well; the love of
speculating upon character, the motives to action, the prin-
ciples of conduct, may deter the mere readers for amuse-
ment, since <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> is manifestly a teacher of men, and is to
be estimated rightly only in that character. He had selected
prose fiction, we imagine, only as a vehicle for conveying
certain pictures of life, portraits of individuals, certain whole-
some moral satire, an ideal of contented private enjoyments,
and of a life of action, enlightened duty. His invention
is probably, therefore, voluntary, and the offspring of ready
impulse. Hence a want of the popular manner and of the
<q>“taking”<q> style. He is not a popular writer, and has,
rightly, not aimed at popularity. This he confesses, and
justifies with sense and honesty. His real mind—the cast of
a writer’s mind must be popular, to render his writings
such, yet there is no element of that kind in our author’s
intellectual constitution. He is too honest to disguise his
defects to individuals; too sincere to please the literary mob.
He is sure of the aristocracy of genius and scholarship and
true worth; the class composed of the wisest and best—the
true aristocracy. To take an elevated example, he, like <persName><author>Mil-
ton<author><persName>, will always be read by the choice few, while, like him,
he must remain caviere to the mass of readers. <p>

<p>We insinuate nothing, byway of comparison between the
two; for <persName><author>Milton<author><persName> is first among the greatest, while <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>
would be too wise to accept of a place among the greatest at
all. He is first among the lesser lights, the <emphasis><foreignphrase>Dii Minores<foreignphrase><emphasis> of
our literary firmament.<p>

<p>The facts of <persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana’s<author><subject><persName> literary career are known to few.
Beside the history of his literary connexions, mentioned be-
fore, we have heard of little else. We once heard <persName><subject><author>Mr, D.<author><subject><persName>
speak of his life as passed in his room. He has been much of
an invalid, and has led, we understand, a retired life. The
only account the public at large, even here, at home, have
of one of the first men we can point to, is to be found in
<title>Blackwood’s Magazine<title> for <date>1824<date> or <date>5<date>. It occurs in a para-
graph, in a series of papers on American writers, ascribed to
<persName><author>John Neal<author><persName>, and evidently from his pen. It is instinct with
the shrewdness and sense of that very clever man, and dash-
ed off in his slashing off-hand style. Without a number of
the Magazine by us, we must quote from memory. <persName><author>Neal<author><persName>
complains of <persName><subject><author>Dana’s<author><subject><persName> indolence and careful polish; though he
gives high and just praise for soundness, purity, and true
genius, he adds certain censure on his excessive care, some-
what after this manner. Dance (a misprint) is pure, sound,
full of genius, but timid, where he has a fair chance, shuts
the wrong eye and is apt to miss. Fond of carving heads,
or cherry stones with his friend <persName><author>Bryant<author><persName>; but the public care
nothing for the <emphasis><foreignphrase>otto<foreignphrase><emphasis> of prose. <persName>Neal<persName> says, that he almost
ruined himself and damned <title>the North American Review<title>,
by an article on <title>Hazlitt’s Poets<title>—an exaggerated sentence in
the true <persName><author>John Neal<author><persName> style. When or how long <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> edited
<title>the North American Review<title>, we cannot exactly discern.
Two only of his reviews have attracted much attention—on
<persName><author>Moore<author><persName> and on <persName><author>Hazlitt’s<author><persName> lectures—the latter harsh, and we
think, unjust. <persName><subject><author>Mr. Dana<author><subject><persName> thinks (or did think) <persName><author>Hazlitt<author><persName> very
much inferior to the notion his admirers entertain of him.
The paper on <persName><author>Moore<author><persName> is just, manly, and creditable to the
critic’s heart, as well as his taste. Much excellent matter is
doubtless buried under a heap of quarterly rubbish. <persName><author>Neal<author><persName>,
in a concluding sentence, reproves our author for his silence
and indolence, stating that <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> had done in several years
as much as he (<persName><author>Neal<author><persName>) could have done in as many weeks or
months. Very likely, but with a difference; with a different
quality, we make bold to think, however, and hardly destined
to survive its year or deeds. <persName><author>Neal<author><persName>, with great cleverness,
and wit, and industry, has furnished hardly anything, except
a few critical sketches and moral essays, with a few brilliant
tales, that show how much more might have been accom-
plished. <persName><author>Neal<author><persName> could have been the first magazine writer of
his day; but he could never equal <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>, lacking, as he does,
the profound and subtle genius of the latter.<p>

<p>In a general survey of the genius of <persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName>, we may remark
his defect of wit and humor. He sometimes indulges in
playful sarcasm, as in the letters from town (would he had
given us more), which are models of their kind—elegant,
familiar, and Addisonian, in the best sense—the natural union
of sense and gaiety, of reflection and feeling.<p>

<p><persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> is a master of characters: his observation is keen
and benevolent, and can at the same time grapple with vig-
orous and strongly-marked characters. He has painted a
character in <title>the First Letter<title>, which somewhat resembles his
own; and which, together with the character of <persName><character>Edward<character><persName>,
and a few touches (of the maiden kind) in the youthful cha-
racter of <persName><character>Paul Felton<character><persName>, go to make up a pretty fair and just
idea of the author.<p>

<p><persName><subject><author>Dana<author><subject><persName> has more imagination than fancy, and which gives
his fictions the air of reality. He is too habitually serious to
be fanciful or fantastic. His imagination delights in tragic
situations, and dark characters, and terrible deeds, that carry
a fearful moral with them. His style is admirable; close,
clear, precise, final. He is equally powerful in his critical
capacity, as he is an original writer. His essays are musings,
the finest reflections of a scholar, and many given to reverie
and sentimental disquisition. The man, too, is but the natu-<pb>
ral converse of the author—kind, sincere, honorable; with-
out a meanness, without a flaw—such is <persName><subject><author>Richard H. Dana<author><subject><persName>,
one of our very best writers; one of our very best men.<p>

<p><authorinitials><author>J.<author><authorinitials><p><close><div>
    </body>
    <back>
      <!-- here is a sample place for contextual information: -->
      <div type="editorial">
        <listPerson>
          <person>
            <persName><!-- canonical name --></persName>
            <birth>
              <placeName><!-- where born; date on when= of <birth> --></placeName>
            </birth>
            <death>
              <placeName><!-- where died; date on when= of <death> --></placeName>
            </death>
          </person>
        </listPerson>
      </div>
    </back>
  </text>
</TEI>
