<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<TEI
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
    xmlns:math="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
    xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The Broadway Journal VOL. 1, NO. 16</title>
                <author>John Bisco</author>
                <respStmt>
                    <name>Gayle</name>
                    <resp>encoder</resp>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>
                    <title>The Broadway Journal</title>
          is project of Louisiana State University
        </p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc default="false">
                <p>
          blah blah blah
        </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text><body><div><head>THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</head><lb/>
<ab>VOL. 1.	NEW YORK, SATURDAY, APRIL 19, 1845.<lb/>
C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.<lb/>
NO. 16.<lb/>
Published at 153 Broadway,<lb/>
By JOHN BISCO.</ab><lb/>
<div>        <lb/>
<head><title>STREET-PAVING.</title></head><p><lb/>
There is, perhaps, no point in the history of the useful arts<lb/>
more remarkable than the fact, that during the last two thou-<lb/>
sand years, the world has been able to make no essential<lb/>
improvements in road-making. It may well be questioned<lb/>
if the Gothamites of 3345 will distinguish any traces of our<lb/>
Third Avenue:—and in the matter of street-pavement, pro-<lb/>
perly so called, although of late, universal attention has been<lb/>
directed to the subject, and experiment after experiment has<lb/>
been tried, exhausting the ingenuity of all modern engineers,<lb/>
it appears that we have at last settled on a result which<lb/>
differs in no material degree, and in principle not at all, from<lb/>
that which the Romans attained, as if instinctively, in the<lb/>
Via Appia, the Via Flaminia, the Via Valeria, the Via Tus-<lb/>
culana, and others. There are streets in Pompeii to-day<lb/>
constructed on the very principle which is considered best by<lb/>
the moderns: or if there be any especial variation, it cer-<lb/>
tainly is not to the credit of modem ingenuity.<lb/>
The most durable and convenient of the Roman roads<lb/>
were thus composed:—The direction and breadth were<lb/>
first marked out by two shallow parrallel furrows or trench-<lb/>
es (sulci) from 15 to 8 feet apart, according to the importance<lb/>
of the via. The loose earth between the trenches was then<lb/>
taken away, and the soil farther removed until a sufficiently<lb/>
solid foundation was reached upon which to deposit the ma-<lb/>
terials of the bed :—if from any cause, such as swampiness,<lb/>
no such natural basis was atttainable, piles (fistucationes)<lb/>
were driven. Above the natural or artificial basis (the gre-<lb/>
mium) four strata were laid, of which the first (statumen)<lb/>
consisted of stones about three times the size of those em-<lb/>
ployed by us in Macadamizing; next came the rudus, brok-<lb/>
en stones, cemented with lime (answering to our rubble-work)<lb/>
—this was generally nine inches thick, and densely rammed.<lb/>
Then came the nucleus of broken earthen-ware, six inches<lb/>
thick, and also cemented with lime. Lastly came the true<lb/>
pavement, (pavimentum) which was composed of irregular<lb/>
Polygons of silex, commonly basaltic lava. These blocks,<lb/>
however, were fitted together with great nicety, and pre-<lb/>
sented just such an appearance as do our best built polygon-<lb/>
al stone walls. The centre of the way was slightly elevated,<lb/>
as with us, above the curb-stones. Now and then, in cities,<lb/>
rectangular slabs of softer stone were substituted for the ir-<lb/>
regular lava polygons—and here the resemblance to the fa-<lb/>
vorite modern mode was nearly complete. When the road<lb/>
or street passed over or through solid rock, the statumen and<lb/>
rudus were neglected, but the nucleus was never dispensed<lb/>
with. On each side of the way were elevated foot-paths,<lb/>
gravelled, and well supported; and at regular intervals<lb/>
Were stone blocks, corresponding to our own steps, for the<lb/>
convenience of horsemen or carriages. Our mile-stones were<lb/>
also employed.<lb/>
We are aware that all this is very school-boyish informa-<lb/>
tion— but we venture to place it before our readers by way<lb/>
of fairly collating the ancient and modem ideas on the gene-<lb/>
ral topic of road-making, and by way, also, of insisting on<lb/>
the observation with which we commenced—that it is ex-<lb/>
ceedingly remarkable how little we have done to advance<lb/>
an art of so vast an importance, notwithstanding the contin-<lb/>
uous endeavors which have been made, and are still mak-<lb/>
ing, to advance it.<lb/>
The Roman road (and our own quadrangular stone-block<lb/>
pavement is but a weak imitation of it) is beyond doubt ex-<lb/>
ceedingly durable; and, so far, wherever the experiment<lb/>
has been tried, it has fully succeeded. By so far we mean<lb/>
so far as concerns durability. The objections are first, its<lb/>
cost, which is very great when the proper material is em-<lb/>
ployed ; and secondly the street din which is wrought by<lb/>
the necessity of having the upper surfaces of the blocks<lb/>
roughened, to afford a hold for the hoof. The noise from<lb/>
these roughened stones is less, certainly, than the tintamar-<lb/>
re proceeding from the round ones—but nevertheless is in-<lb/>
tolerable still. The first objection (cost) is trivial where<lb/>
funds are at command ; for in the end this species of pave-<lb/>
ment is the cheapest which has ever been invented, or prob-<lb/>
ably ever will be invented—for repairs are scarcely needed<lb/>
at all. But it is cheap only in a save-at-the-spigot under-<lb/>
standing of the term—for our second objection is one of a vi-<lb/>
tal importance. The loss of time (not to mention temper)<lb/>
through the insufferable nuisance of street-noise in many of<lb/>
our most frequented thoroughfares, would overwhelm all<lb/>
reasonable people with astonishment if but once fairly and<lb/>
mathematically put ; and that time is money—to an Ameri-<lb/>
can at least—is a proposition not for an instant to be disput-<lb/>
ed. Nor have we dwelt upon the vast inconvenience, and<lb/>
often fatal injury resulting to invalids from the nuisance of<lb/>
which we complain—and of which all classes complain,<lb/>
without ever mentioning the necessity of getting it abated.<lb/>
It is generally admitted, we believe, that as long as they<lb/>
last, the wooden pavements have the advantage over all oth-<lb/>
ers. They occasion little noise (we place this item first and<lb/>
are serious in so placing it as the most important considera-<lb/>
tion of all); they are kept clean with little labor; they save<lb/>
a great deal in horse power ; they are pleasant to the hoof<lb/>
and thus save the health of the horse—as well as some twen-<lb/>
ty or thirty per cent, in the wear and tear of vehicles—and as<lb/>
much more, in time, to all travellers through the increased<lb/>
rapidity of passage to and fro.<lb/>
The first objection is that of injury to the public health<lb/>
from miasmata arising from the wood. Whether such injury<lb/>
actually does occur is very questionable—but there is no need<lb/>
of mooting the question, since all admit that the source of<lb/>
the miasma (decay) can be prevented. It is demonstrated<lb/>
that by the process very improperly called Kyanizing (since<lb/>
Kyan has not the slightest claim to the invention) even the<lb/>
greenest wood may be preserved for centuries, or if need be<lb/>
for a hundred, or far more. The experiments by which this<lb/>
fact is, as we say, demonstrated, have been tried in every<lb/>
variety of way, with nearly identical results. Elocks prop-<lb/>
erly prepared, for example, were subjected for many years,<lb/>
in the fungus pit of the dockyard at Woolwich, England, to<lb/>
242<pb n="242"/><lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
all the known decomposing agents which can ever naturally<lb/>
be brought to act against a wooden pavement, and yet were<lb/>
taken from the pit, at the close of the experiments, in as<lb/>
sound a condition as when originally deposited.<lb/>
The preservative agent employed was that of corrosive<lb/>
sublimate—the Bi-chloride of Mercury. Let a pound of the<lb/>
sublimate be dissolved in fifteen or sixteen gallons of wa-<lb/>
ter, and a piece of any wood (not decayed) be immersed for<lb/>
seventy-two hours in the solution, and the wood cannot af-<lb/>
terwards be rotted. An instantaneous mineralization can be<lb/>
effected, if necessary, by injection of the fluid in vacuo into<lb/>
the pores of the wood. It is rendered much heavier, and<lb/>
more brittle by the process, and has altogether a slightly<lb/>
metallic character.<lb/>
The cost of the Bi-chloride of Mercury is we presume, at<lb/>
present, something less than one dollar per pound—but the<lb/>
cost would be greatly reduced should the mineralizing pro-<lb/>
cess occasion an unusual demand. The South American<lb/>
quicksilver mines, now unworked, would be put into opera-<lb/>
tion, and we should get the article, perhaps, for forty or even<lb/>
thirty cents per pound. But even now the cost of Kyanizing<lb/>
is trifling in comparison with that of cutting, squaring, and<lb/>
roughening stone—to say nothing of the difference in cost<lb/>
between wood itself, and such stone as our present pavements<lb/>
demand.<lb/>
Decay being thus prevented, all danger from miasma is of<lb/>
course to be left out of question ; and although it has been<lb/>
frequently assert d that the mercurial effluvium is injurious<lb/>
to health—the assertion has been as frequently refuted in the<lb/>
most positive and satisfactory manner. The mercury is too<lb/>
closely assimilated with the wooden fibre to admit of any<lb/>
perceptible effluvium. Even where sailors have lived for<lb/>
months in the most confined holds of vessels built of the min-<lb/>
eralized wood, no ill consequences have been found to arise.<lb/>
We write this article with no books before us, and are<lb/>
by no means positive about the accuracy of our details. The<lb/>
general principles and facts, however, are not, we believe,<lb/>
matters of dispute. We confess ourselves, therefore, at a<lb/>
loss to understand how, or why it is, that a Kyanized wood-<lb/>
en pavement to a limited extent, has not been laid (if only<lb/>
by way of a forlorn-hope-like experiment) in some of our<lb/>
public thoroughfares. Or are we merely ignorant of the<lb/>
case—and has the experiment been fairly tried, and found<lb/>
wanting ?</p></div><lb/>
<div>        <lb/>
<head><title>AMUSEMENTS OF NEW YORK.</title></head><lb/>
<p>The supposed proneness of Americans (United Statesers)<lb/>
to labor too much and play too little, has long been a subject<lb/>
of reproach with foreigners, and of complaint among our own<lb/>
countrymen. One of our magazines a short time since con-<lb/>
tained a homily from a city clergyman, in which the evils of<lb/>
too great seriousness of demeanor were forcibly set forth, and<lb/>
people were urged to give more time to recreation and less to<lb/>
business, in a very impressive and serious manner. But these<lb/>
reproaches and complaints are made with a total blindness to<lb/>
the statistics of fun, and with little argument as to the truth<lb/>
of the assumption that Americans are not food of amuse-<lb/>
ments. It is true that we have nothing that resembles the<lb/>
impromptu cotillions which seem to belong to the soil of<lb/>
France, and that fandangos and polkas are not danced by our<lb/>
Broadway ladies in the Park and Bowling-Green; but we<lb/>
doubt whether there are more dancers in Paris, if the figu-<lb/>
rantes of the opera be excepted, than there are in New<lb/>
York. In France they dance by daylight in the open air, for<lb/>
economy’s sake, but here they dance at night in well lighted<lb/>
rooms. The French dance, as though dancing were a matter<lb/>
of course, in a trifling light-hearted manner; here we make<lb/>
a serious business of it, and amuse ourselves in this manner<lb/>
as though it were a duty. Our balls are conducted with as<lb/>
much solemnity and consideration as our courts or elections.<lb/>
Committees are appointed to make suitable arrangements ;<lb/>
guests are invited in a precise sedate mannner, and they dress<lb/>
themselves with elaborate care, to show that they are fully<lb/>
impressed with the importance of the act in which they are<lb/>
to engage, namely—to amuse themselves. Instead of that<lb/>
light and frivolous behaviour which the French manifest on<lb/>
such occasions, showing that they have no sense of the true<lb/>
aim of amusement, which is to improve the health and<lb/>
spirits, our people prove by their solemnity of carriage and<lb/>
gravity of face, that they fully understand what they are<lb/>
about, and that they have engaged in their amusements with<lb/>
an intelligent appreciation of their importance. You may<lb/>
sometimes observe an auctioneer who has rattled away at<lb/>
his vocation all day as light-hearted as a parrot, and as full<lb/>
of grimace as a monkey, go to his amusements with his wife<lb/>
in the evening as sedate and well behaved as a judge. So<lb/>
there are lawyers and judges, as thoughtless as crickets<lb/>
while engaged in the business of their clients, bandying jokes<lb/>
and making awful puns in law Latin, who will go to a ball<lb/>
or a soirée as seriously as though they were disappointed<lb/>
clients. This resolute determination to be amused certainly<lb/>
manifests anything but an indifference to recreations, and it<lb/>
is very plain that the foreigners who have complained of our<lb/>
too close application to business, took but a very superficial<lb/>
view of the national idiosyncrasies. Mr. Dickens looked out<lb/>
from the windows of the Carbon House the day after his<lb/>
arrival in New York, and not seeing any dancing monkeys<lb/>
or organ-grinders in Broadway, directly wrote down in his<lb/>
Diary that we had no amusements. But of all other men in<lb/>
the world he should have been the last to accuse us of a dis-<lb/>
inclination to amuse ourselves, for it was made a gala day<lb/>
whenever he appeared.<lb/>
The public amusements of New York are very numerous ;<lb/>
a glance at one of the morning papers, will at any time dis-<lb/>
cover a greater number of public places of amusement than<lb/>
any city in Europe of the same extent can show. There are at<lb/>
all times six theatres and a circus open nightly, while there<lb/>
are two other theatres closed, on account of the season. Be-<lb/>
sides these theatres, there are two museums where dramatic<lb/>
entertainments are presented, and every night in the week<lb/>
there are dramatic readings and singing in public lecture<lb/>
rooms. The places where free entertainments, in the shape<lb/>
of music and singing are given, are very numerous, and pri-<lb/>
vate balls and parties are innumerable.<lb/>
The theatres, which are generally looked upon as places<lb/>
of amusement only, are generally exceedingly dull and som-<lb/>
bre ; and people who wish to enjoy a hearty laugh, resort to<lb/>
the company of a few choice fellows who have the reputa-<lb/>
tion of saying good things, or seek the companionship of some<lb/>
author who can be warranted not to tire.<lb/>
Amusement should be spontaneous, or rather there can be<lb/>
no amusement which is not so. The theatre should afford<lb/>
amusement, pastime and instruction, but it rarely affords<lb/>
either, and still more rarely the three combined. There is<lb/>
evidence enough around us that we are an amusement seek-<lb/>
ing people, and that we do not, as has been falsely charged,<lb/>
give too much of our lime to serious business; if we gave<lb/>
more we should doubtless be benefitted by it.<lb/>
But we seek our amusements in our own way, and foreign<lb/>
visiters, missing the street shows to which they have been<lb/>
accustomed, very irrationally set us down in their diaries as<lb/>
an overtasked people, who sacrifice every enjoyment to the<lb/>
almighty dollar.<lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
243<pb n="243"/><lb/>
The city governors have always indulged freely in recrea-<lb/>
tions, setting an example to the people which they have not<lb/>
been slow to imitate; but if they should spend part of the<lb/>
time which they devote to feasting and merry-making, in<lb/>
devising means to keep the streets in a healthy condition, the<lb/>
people would hardly complain that they overtasked them-<lb/>
selves with hard labor.<lb/>
A walk through Broadway of a sunny morning to a man<lb/>
of business as he goes to his office, would be recreation<lb/>
enough to sweeten his hours of toil, but in the present con-<lb/>
dition of our noble thoroughfare, it is a weariness and dis-<lb/>
gust to make one’s way through it. The past week it has<lb/>
been perilous to the lungs and the eyes, and certain ruin to<lb/>
one’s clothes. Clouds of dust, soot, ashes, pulverised bricks,<lb/>
and all manner of dried substances which have been ground<lb/>
beneath the wheels of incessant omnibuses, have been drift-<lb/>
ing about in dense masses; the raw wind rushing through<lb/>
the narrow streets, though apparently impatient to escape<lb/>
from such unpleasant places, will stop in Broadway on pur-<lb/>
pose to play with the dust, and fling it into the eyes and nos-<lb/>
trils of pedestrians. Yet people who suffer these inconve-<lb/>
niences will yet talk of amusements, and allow their servants,<lb/>
the rulers of the city, to amuse themselves, while their<lb/>
grievances are unredressed. Nero has been condemned to<lb/>
infamous notoriety, for amusing himself with his fiddle while<lb/>
Rome was burning; but the spectacle of our mayor and alder,<lb/>
men taking a pleasure excursion in a steamboat, or feasting<lb/>
themselves at Bellevue, while the highways of the city are<lb/>
choked with dirt, and the inhabitants are suffocated with<lb/>
dust, is a sight to make the world forget Nero and his fiddle.<lb/>
If a stranger to our country should desire to get a correct<lb/>
idea of the earnestness with which we pursue the phantom<lb/>
pleasure, let him behold the indomitable perseverance which<lb/>
our citizens have shown in the determination to extract en-<lb/>
joyment from the representation of Fashion at the Park thea-<lb/>
tre, and of Antigone at Mr. Dinneford’s; a disinterested ob-<lb/>
server would be convinced that people who went so seriously<lb/>
to work in seeking their amusements, should not be taxed<lb/>
with the sin of devoting too much time to business matters.</p></div><lb/>
<div><head><title>REFORM.</title></head>
<p>One of those innocent persons who conceive themselves to<lb/>
have been sent into the world, like Mr. Moddle, on a mis-<lb/>
sion, has recently taken it into his head to abuse our Journal<lb/>
roundly in an eastern paper, on the assumed ground that we<lb/>
are opposed to reform. This assumption is mainly based upon<lb/>
our remarks upon Miss Fuller’s “Woman in the Nineteenth<lb/>
Ceutury.” Our eyes are not shut to the evils of society, nor<lb/>
are we by any means indifferent about their existence, for we<lb/>
happen to experience personal discomforts every day, which<lb/>
are owing to some abuse of law or custom that might better<lb/>
be abolished than not; but we have learned to take our daily<lb/>
rubs coolly, and we can look upon the sufferings of others<lb/>
with quite as much composure as we can endure our own.<lb/>
We have but little faith in the plan which our modern reform-<lb/>
ers adopt, of scolding the world into good behavior; and we<lb/>
have less faith still in the efficacy of societies to reform abuses,<lb/>
particularly the abuses of foreign governments. Our reform-<lb/>
ers are too apt to forget that "the earth is the Lord’s," and<lb/>
trust to Him too little to provide for the happiness of his<lb/>
children, trusting loo much to themselves. Every man has<lb/>
it in his own power to reform himself, and when he has done<lb/>
that well, he is in a capital condition to help reform the<lb/>
world, but not before. There are some excellent hints on this<lb/>
subject in the Bible, which would do our eastern friend peculiar<lb/>
good, if he were to meditate on them whenever he may feel<lb/>
disposed to hurl his arrows at supposed non-reformers, like<lb/>
ourselves. We do not believe in the existence of individual or<lb/>
isolated vices in a society; it is, therefore, an idle task to at-<lb/>
tempt to heal it of any one disorder. The whole system must<lb/>
be purged of its evil humors. If we concentrate ail our ener-<lb/>
gies in the endeavor to remove a particular evil, all the others<lb/>
will grow the more vigorously for being neglected; while we<lb/>
are trying to cure the world of gambling, licentiousness and<lb/>
avarice and lying and oppression and thievery and drunken-<lb/>
ness will grow in strength. The whole body must be phy-<lb/>
sicked, and not one of its members, to restore it to health.<lb/>
It is unfortunate for those unhappy persons who arrogate<lb/>
to themselves the divine title of reformers, that they gener-<lb/>
ally forget to reform themselves, and they consequently make<lb/>
as ridiculous a figure in the world as the fat man in the mob<lb/>
that Dean Swift tells of, who kept complaining of the crowd<lb/>
until a by-stander reminded him that it was his own carcass<lb/>
that caused all the inconvenience, and that there would be<lb/>
room enough if he were only out of the way.<lb/>
The true reformers of the world are those who scatter<lb/>
truths ; it matters not a straw what they are. Every dis-<lb/>
covery in what are called the physical sciences, obliterates<lb/>
some moral evil. The man with the most knowledge is the<lb/>
greatest reformer, but the converse of this proposition is sup-<lb/>
posed to be the case, and the country is overrun with witlings<lb/>
who set about reforming society before they have mastered<lb/>
their alphabets. In all countries, but in ours above all, the<lb/>
intelligence of the people is the law; therefore it is better to<lb/>
aim at enlightening the people, than to get up a crusade<lb/>
against the law itself. The statute books of England and the<lb/>
United States are full of dead laws, strangled by the intelli-<lb/>
gence of the people, but not repealed. The law of capital<lb/>
punishment is dying daily ; the progress of a certain trial the<lb/>
past week, proves that it is almost dead. It is well for a bad<lb/>
law to be repealed the moment that its wickedness is felt,<lb/>
but the philanthropist need give himself no uneasiness about<lb/>
it; let him instruct the people, and the law will die of itself.<lb/>
Ignorance is the great father of law, and when the law is in<lb/>
advance of the people, they will make laws for themselves,<lb/>
like the Lynch-laws of the west. If we take a glance at the<lb/>
history of the world, we shall find that all the reformers have<lb/>
been poets or the discoverers of truths in science, while pra-<lb/>
ters about reform have left the world quite as full of error as<lb/>
they found it. Milton’s Comus has doubtless done much<lb/>
towards reforming the world, but his Tetrachordon, and other<lb/>
tracts, which were intended expressly to reform it, have done<lb/>
nothing.<lb/>
Our abusive friend is doubtless very sincere in his belief<lb/>
that the world is to be reformed by newspaper paragraphs,<lb/>
and we wish him nothing worse than that he may live to<lb/>
see his faith verified.<lb/></p></div>
<div><head><title>BON-BON.</title></head>
<p>Quand unbon vin meuble mon estomac,<lb/>
Je suis plus savant que Balzac—<lb/>
Plus sage que Pibrac ;<lb/>
Mon bras seul faisant l’attaque<lb/>
De la nation Cossaque,<lb/>
La mettroit au sac;<lb/>
De Charon Je passerois le lac<lb/>
En dormant dans son bac;<lb/>
J’irois au fier Eac,<lb/>
Sans que mon cœur fit tic ni tac,<lb/>
Presenter du tabac.<lb/>
That Pierre Bon-Bon was a restaurateur of uncommon<lb/>
qualifications, no man who, during the reign of---------—, fre-<lb/>
quented the little Cafe in the cul-de-sac Le Febvre at Rouen,<lb/>
will imagine, feel himself at liberty to dispute. That<lb/>
Pierre Bon-Bon was, in an equal degree, skilled in the phil<lb/>
244<pb n="244"/><lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
osophy of that period is, I presume, still more especially un-<lb/>
deniable. His patés à la fois were beyond doubt immacu-<lb/>
late : but what pen can do justice to his essays sur la Nature<lb/>
—his thoughts sur I'Ame—his observations sur VEsprit ? If<lb/>
his omelettes—if his fricandeaux were inestimable, what lit-<lb/>
térateur of that day would not have given twice as much (or<lb/>
an “ Idée de Bon-Bon"  as for all the trash of all the “ Idées"<lb/>
of all the rest of the savants ? Bon-Bon had ransacked libra-<lb/>
ries which no other man had ransacked—had read more than<lb/>
any other would have entertained a notion of reading—had<lb/>
understood more than any other would have conceived the<lb/>
possibility of understanding; and although, while he flour-<lb/>
ished, there were not wanting some authors at Rouen to as-<lb/>
sert “ that his dicta evinced neither the purity of the Acade-<lb/>
my, nor the depth of the Lyceum”—although, mark me, his<lb/>
doctrines were by no means very generally comprehended,<lb/>
still it did not follow that they were difficult of comprehen-<lb/>
sion. It was, I think, on account of their self-evidency that<lb/>
manv persons were led to consider them abstruse. It is to<lb/>
Bon-Bon—but let this go no farther —it is to Bon-Bon that<lb/>
Kant himself is mainly indebted for his metaphysics. The<lb/>
former was indeed not a Platonist, nor strictly speaking an<lb/>
Aristotelian—nor did he, like the modern Leibnitz, waste<lb/>
those precious hours which might be employed in the inven-<lb/>
tion of a fricasée, or, facili gradú, the analysis of a sensation,<lb/>
in frivolous attempts at reconciling the obstinate oils and wa-<lb/>
ters of ethical discussion. Not at all. Bon-Bon was Ionic<lb/>
—Bon-Bon was equally Italic. He reasoned à priori—He<lb/>
reasoned also à posteriori. His ideas were innate—or<lb/>
otherwise. He believed in George of Trebizond—He be-<lb/>
lieved in Bossarion. Bon-Bon was emphatically a—Bon-<lb/>
Bonist.<lb/>
I have spoken of the philosopher in his capacity of restau-<lb/>
rateur. I would not, however, have any friend of mine im-<lb/>
agine that, in fulfilling his hereditary duties in that line, our<lb/>
hero wanted a proper estimation of their dignity and impor-<lb/>
tance. Far from it. It was impossible to say in which<lb/>
branch of his profession he took the greater pride. In his<lb/>
opinion the powers of the intellect held intimate connec-<lb/>
tion with the capabilities of the stomach. I am not sure,<lb/>
indeed, that he greatly disagreed with the Chinese, who<lb/>
hold that the soul lies in the abdomen. The Greeks at all events<lb/>
were right, he thought, who employed the same word for<lb/>
the mind and the diaphragm.* By this I do not mean to<lb/>
insinuate a charge of gluttony, or indeed any other serious<lb/>
charge to the prejudice of the metaphysician. If Pierre Bon-<lb/>
Bon had his failings—and what great man has not a thou-<lb/>
sand ?—if Pierre Bon-Bon, I say, had his failings, they were<lb/>
failings of very little importance—faults indeed which, in<lb/>
other tempers, have often been looked upon rather in the<lb/>
light of virtues. As regards one of these foibles, I should not<lb/>
even have mentioned it in this history but for the remarka-<lb/>
ble prominency—the extreme alto relievo—in which it jut-<lb/>
ted out from the plane of his general disposition.—He could<lb/>
never let slip an opportunity of making a bargain.<lb/>
Not that he was avaricious—no.	It was by no means<lb/>
necessary to the satisfaction of the philosopher, that the bar-<lb/>
gain should be to his own proper advantage. Provided a<lb/>
trade could be effected—a trade of any kind, upon any terms,<lb/>
or under any circumstances—a triumphant smile was seen<lb/>
for many days thereafter to enlighten his countenance, and a<lb/>
knowing wink of the eye to give evidence of his sagacity.<lb/>
At any epoch it would not be very wonderful it a humor<lb/>
so peculiar as the one I have just mentioned, should elicit<lb/>
attention and remark. At the epoch of our narrative, had<lb/>
this peculiarity not attracted observation, there would have<lb/>
been room for wonder indeed. It was soon reported that,<lb/>
upon all occasions of the kind, the smile of Bon-Bon was<lb/>
wont to differ widely from the downright grin with which<lb/>
he would laugh at his own jokes, or welcome an acquain-<lb/>
tance. Hints were thrown out of an exciting nature ; stories<lb/>
were told of perilous bargains made in a hurry and repented<lb/>
of at leisure; and instances were adduced of unaccountable<lb/>
capacities, vague longings, and unnatural inclinations im-<lb/>
planted by the author of all evil for wise purposes of his<lb/>
own.<lb/>
The philosopher had other weakneses—but they are scarce-<lb/>
ly worthy our serious examination. For example, there are<lb/>
few men of extraordinary profundity who are found wanting<lb/>
in an inclination for the bottle. Whether this inclination be<lb/>
an exciting cause, or rather a valid proof, of such profundi-<lb/>
ty, it is a nice thing to say. Bon-Bon, as far as I can learn,<lb/>
did not think the subject adapted to minute investigation;—<lb/>
nor do I. Yet in the indulgence of a propensity so truly clas-<lb/>
sical, it is not to be supposed that the restaurateur would<lb/>
lose sight of that intuitive discrimination which was wont to<lb/>
characterise, at one and the same time, his essais and his<lb/>
omelettes. In his seclusions the Vin de Bourgogne had its al-<lb/>
lotted hour, and there were appropriate moments for the<lb/>
Côtes du Rhone. With him Sauterne was to Medoc what<lb/>
Catullus was to Homer. He would sport with a syllogism<lb/>
in sipping St. Peray, but unravel an argument over Clos de<lb/>
Vougeot, and upset a theory in a torrent of Chamberlin.<lb/>
Well had it been if the same quick sense of propriety had<lb/>
attended him in the peddling propensity to which I have<lb/>
formerly alluded—but this was by no means the case. In-<lb/>
deed, to say the truth, that trait of mind in the philosophic<lb/>
Bon-Bon did begin at length to assume a character of strange<lb/>
intensity and mysticism, and appeared deeply tinctured wilh<lb/>
the diablerie of his favorite German studies.<lb/>
To enter the little Cafe in the Cul-de-Sac Le Febvre was,<lb/>
at the period of our tale, to enter the sanctum of a man of<lb/>
genius. Bon-Bon was a man of genius. There was not a<lb/>
sous-cuisinier in Rouen, who could not have told you that<lb/>
Bon-Bon was a man of genius. His very cat knew it, and<lb/>
forebore to whisk her tail in the presence of the man of ge-<lb/>
nius. His large water-dog was acquainted with the fact,<lb/>
and upon the approach of his master, betrayed his sense of<lb/>
inferiority by a sanctity of deportment, a debasement of the<lb/>
ears, and a dropping of the lower jaw not altogether unwor-<lb/>
thy of a dog. It is, however, true that much of this habitual<lb/>
respect might have been attributed to the personal appear-<lb/>
ance of the metaphysician. A distinguished exterior will, I<lb/>
am constrained to say, have its weight even with a beast;<lb/>
and I am willing to allow much in the outward man of the<lb/>
restaurateur calculated to impress the imagination of the<lb/>
quadruped. There is a peculiar majesty about the atmos-<lb/>
phere of the little great—if I may be permitted so equivocal<lb/>
an expression—which mere physical bulk alone will be found<lb/>
at all times inefficient in creating. If, however, Bon-Bon<lb/>
was barely three feet in height, and if his head was diminu-<lb/>
tively small, still it was impossible to behold the rotundity<lb/>
of his stomach without a sense of magnificence nearly border-<lb/>
ing upon the sublime. In its size both dogs and men must<lb/>
have seen a type of his acquirements—in its immensity a fit-<lb/>
ting habitation for his immortal soul.<lb/>
I might here—if it so pleased me—dilate upon the matter<lb/>
of habiliment, and other mere circumstances of the external<lb/>
metaphysician. I might hint that the hair of our hero was<lb/>
worn short, combed smoothly over his forehead, and sur-<lb/>
mounted by a conical-shaped white flannel cap and tassels—<lb/>
that his pea-green jerkin was not alter the fashion of those<lb/>
worn by the common class of restaurateurs at that day—<lb/>
that the sleeves were something fuller than the reigning cos-<lb/>
tume permitted—that the cuffs were turned up, not as usual<lb/>
in that barbarous period, with cloth of the same quality and<lb/>
color as the garment, but faced in a more fanciful manner<lb/>
with the particolored velvet of Genoa—that his slippers were<lb/>
of a bright purple, curiously filagreed, and might have been<lb/>
manufactured in Japan, but for the exquisite pointing of the<lb/>
toes, and the brilliant tints of the binding and embroidery—<lb/>
that his breeches were of the yellow satin-like material cal-<lb/>
led aimable—that his sky-blue cloak, resembling in form a<lb/>
dressing-wrapper, and richly bestudded all over with crimson<lb/>
devices, floated cavalierly upon his shoulders like a mist of<lb/>
the morning—and that his tout ensemble gave rise to the re-<lb/>
markable words of Benevenuta, the Improvisatrice of Flor-<lb/>
ence, “ that it was difficult to say whether Pierre Bon-Bon<lb/>
was indeed a bird of Paradise, or the rather a very Paradise<lb/>
of perfection."—I might, I say, expatiate upon all these<lb/>
points if I pleased ;—but I forbear:—merely personal details<lb/>
may be left to historical novelists;—they are beneath the<lb/>
moral dignity of matter-of-fact.<lb/>
I have said that “ to enter the Café in the Cul-de-Sac Le<lb/>
Febvre was to enter the sanctum of a man of genius”—but<lb/>
then it was only the man of genius who could duly estimate<lb/>
the merits of the sanctum. A sign consisting of a vast folio<lb/>
swung before the entrance. On one side of the volume was<lb/>
painted a bottle; on the reverse a pate. On the back were<lb/>
visible in large letters the words Œuvres de Bon-Bon. T bus<lb/>
was delicately shadowed forth the two-fold occupation of<lb/>
the proprietor.<lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
245<pb n="245"/><lb/>
Upon stepping over the threshold the whole interior of the<lb/>
building presented itself to view. A long, low pitched room<lb/>
of antique construction, was indeed all the accommodation af-<lb/>
forded by the Càfe. In a corner of the apartment stood the<lb/>
bed of the metaphysician. An array of curtains, together with<lb/>
a canopy à la Greque, gave it an air at once classic and com-<lb/>
fortable. In the corner diagonally opposite, appeared, in di-<lb/>
rect family communion, the properties of the kitchen and the<lb/>
bibliotheque. A dish of polemics stood peacefully upon the<lb/>
dresser. Here lay an oven-full of the latest ethics—there a<lb/>
kettle of duodecimo melanges. Volumes of German morali-<lb/>
ty were hand and glove with the gridiron—a toasting fork<lb/>
might be discovered by the side of Eusebius—Plato reclined<lb/>
at his ease in the frying pan—and contemporary manuscripts<lb/>
were filed away upon the spit.<lb/>
In other respects the Càfe de Bon-Bon might be said to<lb/>
differ little from the usual restaurants of the period. A large<lb/>
fire-place yawned opposite the door. On the right of the<lb/>
fire-place an open cupboard displayed a formidable array of<lb/>
labelled bottles.<lb/>
It was here, about twelve o’clock one night, during the<lb/>
severe winter of-----, that Pierre Bon-Bon, after having lis-<lb/>
tened for some time to the comments of his neighbours<lb/>
upon his singular propensity—that Pierre Bon-Bon, I say,<lb/>
having turned them all out of his house, locked the door up-<lb/>
on them with an oath, and betook himself in no very pacific<lb/>
mood to the comforts of a leather-bottomed arm-chair, and a<lb/>
fire of blazing faggots.<lb/>
It was one of those terrific nights which are only met with<lb/>
once or twice during a century. It snowed fiercely, and the<lb/>
house tottered to its centre with the floods of wind that,<lb/>
rushing through the crannies in the wall, and pouring impet-<lb/>
uously down the chimney, shook awfully the curtains of the<lb/>
philosopher’s bed, and disorganised the economy of his pate-<lb/>
pane and papers. The huge folio sign that swung without,<lb/>
exposed to the fury of the tempest, creaked ominously, and<lb/>
gave out a moaning sound from it stanchions of solid oak.<lb/>
It was in no placid temper, I say, that the metaphysician<lb/>
drew up his chair to its customary station by the hearth.<lb/>
Many circumstances of a perplexing nature had occurred du-<lb/>
ring the day, to disturb the serenity of his meditations. In<lb/>
attempting des œufs à la Princesse he had unfortunately<lb/>
perpetrated an omelete à la Rente ; the discovery of a prin-<lb/>
ciple in ethics had been frustrated by the overturning of a<lb/>
stew; and last, not least, he had been thwarted in one of<lb/>
those admirable bargains which he at all times took such<lb/>
especial delight in bringing to a successful termination. But<lb/>
in the chafing of his mind at these unaccountable vicissi-<lb/>
tudes, there did not fail to be mingled some degree of that<lb/>
nervous anxiety which the fury of a boisterous night is so<lb/>
well calculated to produce. Whistling to his more imme-<lb/>
diate vicinity the large black water-dog we have spoken of<lb/>
before, and settling himself uneasily in his chair, he could<lb/>
not help casting a wary and unquiet eye towards those dis-<lb/>
tant recesses of the apartment whose inexorable shadows<lb/>
not even the red fire-light itself could more than partially<lb/>
succeed in overcoming. Having completed a scrutiny whose<lb/>
exact purpose was perhaps unintelligible to himself, he drew<lb/>
close to his seat a small table covered with books and pa-<lb/>
pers, and soon became absorbed in the task of retouching a<lb/>
Voluminous manuscript, intended for publication on the mor-<lb/>
row.<lb/>
He had been thus occupied for some minutes when “ I am<lb/>
in no hurry, Monsieur Bon-Bon,” suddenly whispered a whin-<lb/>
ing voice in the apartment.<lb/>
“The devil!” ejaculated our hero, starting to his feet,<lb/>
overturning the table at his side, and staring around him in<lb/>
astonishment.<lb/>
“ Very true,” calmly replied the voice.<lb/>
“ Very true!—what is very true?—how came you here ?"<lb/>
vociferated the metaphysician, as his eye fell upon something<lb/>
which lay stretched at full length upon the bed.<lb/>
"I was saying,” said the intruder, without attending to<lb/>
the interrogatories, “ I was saying that I am not at all push-<lb/>
ed for lime—that the business upon which I took the liber-<lb/>
ty of calling is of no pressing importance—in short that I<lb/>
can very well wait until you have finished your Exposition.<lb/>
“ My Exposition !—there now !—how do you know-how<lb/>
came you to understand that I was writing an exposition ?<lb/>
good God!"<lb/>
“ Hush !" replied the figure in a shrill under tone: and,<lb/>
arising quickly from the bed, he made a single step towards<lb/>
our hero, while an iron lamp that depended overhead swung<lb/>
convulsively back from his approach.	6<lb/>
The philosopher’s amazement did not prevent a narrow<lb/>
scrutiny of the stranger’s dress and appearance. The out-<lb/>
lines of a figure, exceedingly lean, but much above the com-<lb/>
mon height, were rendered minutely distinct by means of a<lb/>
faded suit of black cloth which fitted tight to the skin, but<lb/>
was otherwise cut very much in the style of a century ago.<lb/>
These garments had evidently been intended for a much<lb/>
shorter person than their present owner. His ankles and<lb/>
wrists were left naked for several inches. In his shoes,<lb/>
however, a pair of very brilliant buckles gave the lie to the<lb/>
extreme poverty implied by the other portions of his dress.<lb/>
His bead was bare, and entirely bald, with the exception of<lb/>
the hinder part, from which depended a queue of considerable<lb/>
length. A pair of green spectacles, with side glasses, pro-<lb/>
tected his eyes from the influence of the light, and at the<lb/>
same time prevented our hero from ascertaining either their<lb/>
color or their conformation. About the entire person there<lb/>
was no evidence of a shirt; but a white cravat, of filthy ap-<lb/>
pearance, was tied with extreme precision around the throat,<lb/>
and the ends, hanging down formally side by side, gave (al-<lb/>
though I dare say unintentionally) the idea of an ecclesiastic.<lb/>
Indeed, many other points both in his appearance and de-<lb/>
meanour might have very well sustained a conception of that<lb/>
nature. Over his left ear, he carried, after the fashion of a<lb/>
modern clerk, an instrument resembling the stylus of the an-<lb/>
cients. In a breast-pocket of his coat appeared conspicuously<lb/>
a small black volume fastened with clasps of steel. This<lb/>
book, whether accidentally or not, was so turned outwardly<lb/>
from the person as to discover the words “ Rituel Catholique”<lb/>
in white letters upon the back. His entire physiognomy was<lb/>
interestingly saturnine—even cadaverously pale. The fore-<lb/>
head was lofty, and deeply furrowed with the ridges of con-<lb/>
templation. The corners of the mouth were drawn down<lb/>
into an expression of the most submissive humility. There<lb/>
was also a clasping of the hands, as he stepped towards our<lb/>
hero—a deep sigh—and altogether a look of such utter sanc-<lb/>
tity as could not have failed to be unequivocally preposses-<lb/>
sing. Every shadow of anger faded from the countenance of<lb/>
the metaphysician, as, having completed a satisfactory sur-<lb/>
vey of his visiter’s person, he shook him cordially by the<lb/>
hand, and conducted him to a seat.<lb/>
There would however be a radical error in attributing this<lb/>
instantaneous transition of feeling in the philosopher, to any<lb/>
one of those causes which might naturally be supposed to<lb/>
have had an influence. Indeed Pierre Bon-Bon, from what I<lb/>
have been able to understand of his disposition, was of all<lb/>
men the least likely to be imposed upon by any speciousness<lb/>
of exterior deportment. It was impossible that so accurate<lb/>
an observer of men and things should have failed to discover,<lb/>
upon the moment, the real character of the personage who<lb/>
had thus intruded upon his hospitality. To say no more, the<lb/>
conformation of his visiter’s feet was sufficiently remarkable<lb/>
—he maintained lightly upon his head an inordinately tall<lb/>
hat—there was a tremulous swelling about the hinder part<lb/>
of his breeches—and the vibration of his coat tail was a pal-<lb/>
pable fact. Judge then with what feelings of satisfaction our<lb/>
hero found himself thrown thus at once into the society of a<lb/>
person for whom he had at all times entertained the most<lb/>
unqualified respect. He was, however, too much of the di-<lb/>
plomatist to let escape him any intimation of his suspicions<lb/>
in regard to the true state of affairs. It was not his cue to<lb/>
appear at all conscious of the high honor he thus unexpect-<lb/>
edly enjoyed, but by leading his guest into conversation, to<lb/>
elicit some important ethical ideas, which might, in obtaining<lb/>
a place in his contemplated publication, enlighten the human<lb/>
race and at the same time immortalize himself—ideas which,<lb/>
I should have added, his visiter’s great age, and well known<lb/>
proficiency in the science of morals, might very well have<lb/>
enabled him to afford.<lb/>
Actuated by these enlightened views, our hero bade the<lb/>
gentleman sit down, while he himself took occasion to throw<lb/>
some faggots upon the fire, and place upon the now re-estab-<lb/>
lished table some bottles of Mousseux. Having quickly com-<lb/>
pleted these operations, he drew his chair vis-à-vis to his<lb/>
companion’s and waited until the latter should open the con-<lb/>
versation. But plans even the most skillfully matured are<lb/>
often thwarted in the outset of they application, and the<lb/>
restaurateur found himself nonplussed by the very first words<lb/>
of his visiter's speech.<lb/>
"I see you know me, Bon-Bon,” said he: “ha! ha!ha!—<lb/>
246<pb n="246"/><lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
he! he! he !—hi! hi! hi!—ho! ho ! ho!—hu! hu! hu!”—and<lb/>
the devil, dropping at once the sanctity of his demeanour,<lb/>
opened to its fullest extent a mouth from ear to ear, so as to<lb/>
display a set of jagged and fang-like teeth, and throwing back<lb/>
his head, laughed long, loudly, wickedly, and uproariously,<lb/>
while the black dog, crouching down upon his haunches,<lb/>
joined lustily in the chorus, and the tabby cat, flying off at a<lb/>
tangent, stood up on end and shrieked in the farthest corner<lb/>
of the apartment.<lb/>
Not so the philosopher ; he was too much a man of the<lb/>
world either to laugh like the dog, or by shrieks to betray<lb/>
the indecorous trepidation of the cat. It must be confessed,<lb/>
he felt a little astonishment to see the white letters which<lb/>
formed the words “ Rituel Catholique" on the book in his<lb/>
guest’s pocket, momently changing both their color and their<lb/>
import, and in a few seconds, in place of the original title,<lb/>
the words Régitre des Condamnés blaze forth in characters<lb/>
of red. This startling circumstance, when Bon-Bon replied<lb/>
to his visiter’s remark, imparted to his manner an air of em-<lb/>
barrassment which probably might not otherwise have been<lb/>
observed.<lb/>
“Why, sir.” said the philosopher, “why, sir, to speak<lb/>
sincerely—I believe you are—upon my word—the d----dest<lb/>
—that is to say I think—I imagine—I have some faint—<lb/>
some very faint idea—of the remarkable honor------”<lb/>
“ Oh !—ah!—yes!—very well !” interrupted his Majesty,<lb/>
Cl say no more—I see how it is.” And hereupon, taking off<lb/>
his green spectacles, he wiped the glasses carefully with the<lb/>
sleeve of his coat, and deposited them in his pocket.<lb/>
If Bon-Bon had been astonished at the incident of the book,<lb/>
his amazement was now much increased by the spectacle<lb/>
which here presented itself to view. In raising his eves,<lb/>
with a strong feeling of curiosity to ascertain the color of his<lb/>
guest’s, he found them by no means black, as he bad antici-<lb/>
pated—nor gray, as might have been imagined—nor yet ha-<lb/>
zel nor blue—nor indeed yellow nor red—nor purple—nor<lb/>
white—nor green—nor any other color in the heavens above,<lb/>
or in the earth beneath, or in the waters under the earth. In<lb/>
short Pierre Bon-Bon not only saw plainly that his Majesty<lb/>
had no eyes whatsoever, but could discover no indications of<lb/>
their having existed at any previous period ; for the space<lb/>
where eyes should naturally have been, was, I am constrained<lb/>
to say, simply a dead level of flesh.<lb/>
It was not in the nature of the metaphysician to forbear<lb/>
making some inquiry into the sources of so strange a pheno-<lb/>
menon, and the reply of his Majesty was at once prompt, dig-<lb/>
nified, and satisfactory.<lb/>
“ Eyes ! my dear Bon-Bon, eyes! did you say ?—oh ! ah !<lb/>
I perceive. The ridiculous prints, eh ? which are in circu-<lb/>
lation, have given you a false idea of my personal appearance.<lb/>
Eyes !!—true. Eyes, Pierre Bon-Bon, are very well in their<lb/>
proper place—that, you would say, is the head?—right—the<lb/>
ead of a worm. To you likewise these optics are indis-<lb/>
pensable—yet I will convince you that my vision is more<lb/>
penetrating than your own. There is a cat, I see in the<lb/>
corner—a pretty cat!—look at her !—observe her well!<lb/>
Now, Bon-Bon, do you behold the thoughts—the thoughts, I<lb/>
say—the ideas—the reflections—which are being engender-<lb/>
ed in her pericranium ? There it is now !—you do not. She<lb/>
is thinking we admire the length of her tail and the profundi-<lb/>
ty of her mind. She has just concluded that 1 am the most<lb/>
distinguished of ecclesiastics, and that you are the most su-<lb/>
perfluous of metaphysicians. Thus you see I am not alto-<lb/>
gether blind : but to one of my profession the eyes you speak<lb/>
of would be merely an incumbrance, liable at any time to<lb/>
be put out by a toasting iron ora pitchfork. To you, I allow,<lb/>
these optical affairs are indispensable. Endeavor, Bon-Bon,<lb/>
to use them well;—my vision is the soul.”<lb/>
Hereupon the guest helped himself to the wine upon the<lb/>
table, and pouring out a bumper for Bon-Bon, requested him<lb/>
to drink it without scruple, and make himself perfectly at<lb/>
home.<lb/>
“ A clever book that of yours, Pierre,” resumed his Ma-<lb/>
jesty, tapping our friend knowingly upon the shoulder, as the<lb/>
latter put down his glass after a thorough compliance with<lb/>
his visiter’s injunction. " A clever book that of yours, upon<lb/>
my honor. It's a work after my own heart. Your arrange-<lb/>
ment of matter, I think, however, might be improved, and<lb/>
many of your notions remind me of Aristotle. That philo-<lb/>
sopher was one of my most intimate acquaintances. I liked<lb/>
him as much for his terrible ill temper, as for his happy<lb/>
knack at making a blunder. There is only one solid truth in<lb/>
all that he has written, and for that I gave him the hint out<lb/>
of pure compassion for his absurdity. I suppose, Pierre Bon-<lb/>
Bon, you very well know to what divine moral truth I am<lb/>
alluding.”<lb/>
“ Cannot say that I-------”<lb/>
“ Indeed!—why it was I who told Aristotle that by sneez-<lb/>
ing men expelled superfluous ideas through the proboscis.”<lb/>
“Which is—hiccup!—undoubtedly the case,” said the<lb/>
metaphysician, while he poured out for himself another<lb/>
bumper of Mousseux, and offered his snuff-box to the fingers<lb/>
of his visiter.”<lb/>
“ There was Plato, too,” continued his Majesty, modestly<lb/>
declining the snuff-box and the compliment it implied, “ there<lb/>
was Plato, too, for whom I, at one time, felt all the affection<lb/>
of a friend. You knew, Plato, Bon-Bon?—ah! no, I beg a<lb/>
thousand pardons. He met me at Athens, one day, in the<lb/>
Parthenon, and told me he was distressed for an idea. I bade<lb/>
him write down that ο νους εςτιν αυλος. He said that he<lb/>
would do so, and went home, while I stepped over to the<lb/>
pyramids. But my conscience smote me for having uttered a<lb/>
truth, even to aid a friend, and hastening back to Athens, I<lb/>
arrived behind the philosopher’s chair as he was inditing the<lb/>
‘αυλος.’ Giving the lamma a fillip with my finger I turned it<lb/>
upside down. So the sentence now reads ‘ ο νους εςτιν αυγος,'<lb/>
and is, you perceive, the fundamental doctrine in his meta-<lb/>
physics.”<lb/>
“ Were you ever at Rome ?” asked the restaurateur as he<lb/>
finished his second bottle of Mousseux, and drew from the<lb/>
closet a larger supply of Chambertin.<lb/>
“ But once, Monsieur Bon-Bon, but once. There was a<lb/>
time”—said the devil, as if reciting some passage from a<lb/>
book—“ there was a time when occurred an anarchy of five<lb/>
years, during which the republic, bereft of all its officers,<lb/>
had no magistracy besides the tribunes of the people, and<lb/>
these were not legally vested with any degree of executive<lb/>
power—at that time, Monsieur Bon-Bon—at that time only<lb/>
I was in Rome, and I have no earthly acquaintance, conse-<lb/>
quently, with any of its philosophy.”*<lb/>
“ What do you think of—what do you think of—hiccup !<lb/>
—Epicurus ?”<lb/>
“ What do I think of whom?"  said the devil in astonish-<lb/>
ment, “you cannot surely mean to find any fault with Epicu-<lb/>
rus ! What do I think of Epicurus ! Do you mean me, sir ?<lb/>
—I am Epicurus. I am the same philosopher who wrote<lb/>
each of the three hundred treatises commemorated by Dioge-<lb/>
nes Laertes.”<lb/>
“That’s a lie!” said the metaphysician, for the wine had<lb/>
gotten a little into his head.<lb/>
“ Very well!—very well, sir!—very well indeed, sir,” said<lb/>
his Majesty, apparently much flattered.<lb/>
“ That’s a lie!” repeated the restaurateur dogmatically,<lb/>
“ that’s a—hiccup !—a lie!”<lb/>
“Well, well! have it your own way,” said the devil<lb/>
pacifically: and Bon-Bon, having beaten his Majesty at an<lb/>
argument, thought it his duty to conclude a second bottle of<lb/>
Chambertin.<lb/>
“As I was saying,” resumed the visiter, “as I was obser-<lb/>
ving a little while ago, there are some very outre notions in<lb/>
that book of yours, Monsieur Bon-Bon. What, for instance,<lb/>
do you mean by all that humbug about the soul ? Pray, sir,<lb/>
what is the soul ?”<lb/>
“The—hiccup!—soul,” replied the mataphysician,refer-<lb/>
ring to his MS., “ is undoubtedly”—<lb/>
“ No, sir!”<lb/>
“ Indubitably”—<lb/>
“ No, sir!”<lb/>
“ Indisputably”—<lb/>
“ No, sir!"<lb/>
“ Evidently"—<lb/>
“ No, sir!”<lb/>
“ Incontrovertibly”—<lb/>
“ No sir!"<lb/>
“ Hiccup !”—<lb/>
“ No, sir!”<lb/>
“ And beyond all question a”—<lb/>
“No, sir! the soul is no such thing.” (Here, the philosopher<lb/>
looking daggers, took occasion to make an end, upon the<lb/>
spot, of his third bottle of Chambertin.)<lb/>
“ Then —hic-cup !—pray, sir—what—what is it ?"<lb/>
* In escrivaient sur la Philosophi (Cicero, Lucretius, Seneca) mais c'etait<lb/>
la Philosophi Grécque.—Condorcet.<lb/>
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.<lb/>
247<pb n="247"/><lb/>
“ That is neither here nor there, Monsieur Bon-Bon,” re-<lb/>
plied his Majesty, musingly. “I have tasted—that is to say,<lb/>
1 have known some very had souls, and some too—pretty<lb/>
good ones.” Here he smacked his lips, and, having uncon-<lb/>
sciously let fall his hand upon the volume in his pocket, was<lb/>
seized with a violent fit of sneezing.<lb/>
He continued :<lb/>
“ There was the soul of Cratinus—passable: Aristopha-<lb/>
nes—racy : Plato—exquisite—not your Plato, but Plato the<lb/>
comic poet; your Plato would have turned the stomach of<lb/>
Cerberus—faugh ! Then let me see ! there were Nœvius,<lb/>
and Andronicus, and Plautus, and Terentius. Then there<lb/>
were Lucilius, and Catullus, and Naso, and Quintius Flaccus,<lb/>
—dear Quinty ! as I called him when he sung a seculare for<lb/>
my amusement, while I toasted him, in pure good humor, on<lb/>
a fork. But they want flavor these Romans. One fat Greek<lb/>
is worth a dozen of them, and besides will keep, which cannot<lb/>
be said of a Quirite.—Let us taste your Sauterne.”<lb/>
Bon-Bon bad by this time made up his mind to the nil ad-<lb/>
mirari, and endeavored to hand down the bottles in question.<lb/>
He was, however, conscious of a strange sound in the room<lb/>
like the wagging of a tail. Of this, although extremely in-<lb/>
decent in his Majesty, the philosopher took no notice:—sim-<lb/>
ply kicking the dog, and requesting him to be quiet. The<lb/>
visiter continued :<lb/>
“ I found that Horace tasted very much like Aristotle ;—<lb/>
you know I am fond of variety. Terentius I could not have<lb/>
told from Menander. Naso, to my astonishment, was Nican-<lb/>
der in disguise. Virgilius bad a strong twang of Theocritus.<lb/>
Martial put me much in mind of Archilochus—and Titus<lb/>
Livius was positively Polybius and none other.”<lb/>
“ Hic-cup !” here replied Bon-Bon, and his Majesty pro-<lb/>
ceeded :<lb/>
“ But if I have a penchant, Monsieur Bon-Bon—if I have a<lb/>
penchant, it is for a philosopher. Yet, let me tell you, 6ir, it<lb/>
is not every dev—I mean it is not every gentleman who<lb/>
knows how to choose a philosopher. Long ones are not<lb/>
good ; and the best, if not carefully shelled, are apt to be a<lb/>
little rancid on account of the gall."<lb/>
“ Shelled!!”<lb/>
“ I mean taken out of the carcass.”<lb/>
“ What do you think of a—hic-cup!—physician ?’’<lb/>
“ Don't mention them !—ugh ! ugh !” (Here his Majesty<lb/>
retched violently.) “ I never tasted but one—that rascal<lb/>
Hippocrates!—smelt of asafœtida—ugh ! ugh ! ugh !—caught<lb/>
a wretched cold washing him in the Styx—and after all he<lb/>
gave me the cholera morbus.”<lb/>
“The—hiccup!—wretch!” ejaculated Bon-Bon, “ the—<lb/>
hic-cup !—abortion of a pill-box!”—and the philosopher drop-<lb/>
ped a tear.<lb/>
“ After all,” continued the visiter, “ after all, if a dev—if<lb/>
a gentleman wishes to live, he must have more talents than<lb/>
one or two; and with us a fat face is an evidence of diplo-<lb/>
macy.”<lb/>
" How so?”<lb/>
“ Why we are sometimes exceedingly pushed for provi-<lb/>
sions. You must know that, in a climate so sultry as mine,<lb/>
it is frequently impossible to keep a spirit alive for more than<lb/>
two or three hours ; and after death, unless pickled immedi-<lb/>
ately, (and a pickled spirit is not good,) they will—smell—<lb/>
you understand, eh ? Putrefaction is always to be appre-<lb/>
hended when the souls are consigned to us in the usual<lb/>
way.”<lb/>
“ Hiccup!—hiccup !—good God ! how do you manage ?”<lb/>
Here the iron lamp commenced swinging with redoubled<lb/>
violence, and the devil half started from his seat;—however,<lb/>
with a slight sigh, he recovered his composure, merely say-<lb/>
rag to our hero in a low tone, “ I tell you what, Pierre Bon-<lb/>
Bon, we must have no more swearing.”<lb/>
The host swallowed another bumper, by way of denoting<lb/>
thorough comprehension and acquiescence, and the visiter<lb/>
continued:<lb/>
“ Why there are several ways of managing. The most of<lb/>
us starve: some put up with the pickle: for my part I pur-<lb/>
chase my spirits vivente corpore, in which case I find they<lb/>
keep very well."<lb/>
“ But the body !—hiccup!—the body!!!”<lb/>
“ The body, the body—well, what of the body ?—oh! ah !<lb/>
I perceive. Why, sir, the body is not at all affected by the<lb/>
transaction. I have made innumerable purchases of the kind<lb/>
in my day, and the parties never experienced any inconve-<lb/>
nience. There were Cain and Nimrod, and Nero, and Cali-<lb/>
 gula, and Dionysius, and Pisistratus, and—and a thousand<lb/>
others, who never knew what it was to have a soul during<lb/>
the latter part of their lives; yet, sir, these men adorned so-<lb/>
ciety. Why isn’t there A-----, now, whom you know as<lb/>
well as I ? Is he not in possession of all his faculties, men-<lb/>
tal and corporeal ? Who writes a keener epigram ? Who<lb/>
reasons more wittily ? Who——but, stay ! I have his agree-<lb/>
ment in my pocket-book.”<lb/>
Thus saying, he produced a red leather wallet, and took<lb/>
from it a number of papers. Upon some of these Bon-Bon<lb/>
caught a glimpse of the letters Machi—Maza—Robesp—with<lb/>
the words Caligula, George, Elizabeth. His Majesty select-<lb/>
ed a narrow slip of parchment, and from it read aloud the<lb/>
following words:<lb/>
“ In consideration of certain mental endowments which it<lb/>
is unnecessary to specify, and in farther consideration of one<lb/>
thousand louis d’or, I, being aged one year and one month,<lb/>
do hereby make over to the bearer of this agreement all my<lb/>
right, title, and appurtenance in the shadow called my soul.<lb/>
(Signed) A.....* (Here his Majesty repeated a name<lb/>
which I do not feel myself justified in indicating more une-<lb/>
quivocally.)<lb/>
“A clever fellow that,’’ resumed he; ‘‘but like you, Mon-<lb/>
sieur Bon-Bon, he was mistaken about tbe soul. The soul<lb/>
a shadow truly ! The soul a shadow ! Ha ! ha ! ha !—he !<lb/>
he! he!—hu! hu ! hu! Only think of a fricasséed shadow!”<lb/>
“ Only think—hiccup!—of a fricasséed shadow !" exclaim-<lb/>
ed our hero, whose faculties were becoming much illumina-<lb/>
ted by the profundity of his Majesty’s discourse.<lb/>
“ Only think of a—hiccup!—fricasséed shadow!! Now,<lb/>
damme!—hiccup!—humph ! If I would have been such a<lb/>
—hiccup !—nincompoop. My soul, Mr.—humph !”<lb/>
“ Your soul, Monsieur Bon-Bon ?”<lb/>
“ Yes, sir—hiccup !—my soul is”—<lb/>
“What, sir ?”<lb/>
“ No shadow, damme!”<lb/>
“ Did not mean to say”—<lb/>
“ Yes, sir, my soul is—hiccup!—humph!—yes, sir.”<lb/>
“ Did not intend to assert”—<lb/>
“ My soul is—hiccup !—peculiarly qualified for—hiccup |<lb/>
—a”—<lb/>
“What, sir?”<lb/>
“Stew.”<lb/>
“ Ha!”<lb/>
“ Soufflée.”<lb/>
“Eh?”<lb/>
“ Fricassée.”<lb/>
“ Indeed!”<lb/>
“Ragout and fricandeau—and see here, my good fellow !<lb/>
I’ll let you have it—hiccup!—a bargain.” Here the philo-<lb/>
sopher slapped his Majesty upon the back.<lb/>
“ Could’nt think of such a thing,” said the latter calmly,<lb/>
at the same time rising from his seat. The metaphysician<lb/>
stared.<lb/>
“ Am supplied at present,” said his Majesty.<lb/>
“Hiccup!—e-h ?” said the philosopher.<lb/>
"Have no funds on hand.”<lb/>
“ What ?”<lb/>
“ Besides, very unhandsome in me’’—<lb/>
“Sir!”<lb/>
“ To take advantage of”—<lb/>
“Hiccup!”	<lb/>
“ Your present disgusting and ungentlemanly situation.”<lb/>
Here the visiter bowed and withdrew—in what manner<lb/>
could not precisely be ascertained—but in a well-concerted<lb/>
effort to discharge a bottle at “ the villain,” the slender chain<lb/>
was severed that depended from the ceiling, and the meta-<lb/>
physician prostrated by the downfall of the lamp.<lb/>
* Quere—Arouet?</p><lb/></div>
</div></body></text></TEI>